

Phone: 99542298--98201208 E-mail: saud_aljardani@yahoo.com **P.O BOX:** 583,RUWI **POSTAL CODE:** 112

SULTANATE OF OMAN

Saud Ali Habib AL-Jardani

Personal Statement

A highly competent and organized systems administrator with experience of software procurement, installation, administration & compatibility. Possessing a proven ability to assist with the day-to-day running of an IT department and it's business IT systems. Extensive knowledge of monitoring and controlling data security within guidelines to ensure compliance and report on possible improvements. Well mannered, articulate and able to act as point of contact for colleagues and external clients.

Personal Information:

Name: Saud Ali Habib AL-Jardani

Date of Birth: 27/10/1979

Gender: Male

Nationality: Omani Civil #: 03695312

Qualifications

2007-2009

Mazoon College

Muscat

Master of Technology (M.Tech) Computer Science

- Graduation Project: "Customer perception towards internet banking in Oman".
- Major Modules of theory are:
 - Distributed Computing.
 - **Emerging Programming Paradigms.**
 - Knowledge Management and Data Mining.
 - Advanced Computer Architecture.
 - Software Engineering.
 - Data Communication and Network.

- Microprocessor and Microcomputer Applications.
- Advanced Topics in Algorithm.
- Enterprise Resource Planning.
- Artificial Intelligence.
- Seminar.
- Ecommerce.
- Advance Communication Network.
- Major Modules of Practical and Laboratory Practice are:
 - Distributed Computing.
 - Emerging Programming Paradigms.
 - Software Engineering.
 - Microprocessor and Microcomputer Applications.
 - Enterprise Resource Planning (with Oracle).
 - Artificial Intelligence

2006- 2007 Majan College (University College) Darsayt

Bachelor Degree with Honor in Computer and Internet Application.

- Affiliated with the University of Luton, United Kingdom.
- Graduation Project: Registration System For Wadi Hatat Institute.
- Major Modules are:
 - Electronic Enterprises.
 - Database Administration.
 - Information System Management.
 - E-Commerce System.
 - Managing Software Acquisition.
 - Managing Networks.

2003- 2005 Majan College (University College) Darsayt

(HND) Higher National Diploma in Computer and Internet Application.

- Recognized by the University of Luton, United Kingdom.
- Major Modules are
 - Computer Systems and Information Processing (Hardware and Software installation and maintenance).
 - Communication Systems.
 - Networking.
 - Managing Networks.
 - System Analysis and Design.
 - Internet Application.
 - Interface Design Environment (with a project

implemented by Visual Basic).

- Introduction to Programming.
- Data Base.
- Object Oriented programming.
- Data Base Design (with Oracle).
- IT system Building (with Developer 2000 and Oracle).

2002- 2003

Majan College (University College)

Darsayt

Foundation program

- Awarded the Foundation Certificate with Distinction involving a full year of academic study of 34 weeks / 821 hours.
- Recognized by the University of Luton, United Kingdom.

Education

2001 – 2002 Ruwi Secondary School

(Muscat city)

Third Secondary certificate

- Pathway is "Science".
- Major Modules are

(Arabic, English, Physic, Chemistry, Biology and Math).

Some Courses:

- Certificate in English from Al- Raqadi Training Institute.
- Certificate in English from Khalij Oman Institute.
- Certificate in NVQ Induction English.
- National Vocational Qualification Level 2 Performing Engineering Operations.
- Certificate of unit credit.

Job Responsibilities

IT Assistant Manager at National Finance Company (NFC)

- Supervise all daily and weekly IT procedures, report directly to IT Manager.
- Perform installation, configuration and troubleshooting of Hardware,
 Software and communication of POS (Point Of Sale).
- Design; Implement Preventive Maintenance for all IT hardware & Software.
- Responsibility for all IT related issues.
- Will be in charge of IT Dept. when IT Manager absent or out of the country.
- Checking daily backups, all system interfaces, Server hardware and logs.
- Supervision of IT supervisors and clerks.

- Assign IT Staff daily jobs and check lists, train them on all needed theoretical and practical procedures, trouble shooting and support with in corporate standards.
- Claim suppliers for any Software/ Hardware conflicts.
- Follow up all claims that are being forwarded to IT Dept, apply the theory of trouble tickets.
- Documenting, archiving all correspondence and trouble shooting, follow up suppliers' visits and maintenance.
- Develop and adapt any ideas that bring IT services to higher level.
- Recovers any gaps that might face IT Dept.
- Assist existing/new properties when it is required, with approval of IT Manage.

Technical Support Specialist-E-Services Information Technology Dept & Systems Developer-E-Banking at Oman Arab Bank

- Provide IT technical support of POS terminal for payment environment in different area (all branches of Ministry of Manpower, Ministry of Commerce and Industry, Oman Chamber of Commerce and Industry, Organizations, Companies and Hundreds of Sand Offices).
- Perform installation, configuration and troubleshooting of Hardware,
 Software and communication of POS (Point Of Sale).
- Act as the first line support for security applications including E-Payment and E-Service.
- Troubleshoot the network services (Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), are cryptographic protocols that provide communication security over the Internet and Dialup line)
- Ensure timely resolution of all first level problems with minimum supervision.
- Manage end-to-end projects/activities assigned and Develop and maintain the artifacts related to the data analysis as per the best practices.
- Back up and restoring users files and devices configuration.
- Perform the helpdesk activities including responding to telephone calls,
 email and employees' requests for assistance.
- Overseeing the branch operations and managing the day-to-day
 Activities of the branch networking and communications.
- Responsible day to day system operation such as End-of-day, start-of-

day, backups system and creating reports.

- In various computer system such as NCR UNIX Machine, IBM AS/400 and PCs Support.
- Whenever assigned with branch support team, I am responsible for setting PC for the front –end use, installation of PC related Packages, problem solving ranging from hardware related problem to data communication.
- Good knowledge on LAN/WAN.
- Good domain knowledge and experience in troubleshooting various types of LAN cabling hardware, network connectivity issues and possess strong problem solving ability with customer service skills.
- Basic knowledge of communication protocols and equipment's like hubs switches, routers, etc.
- Hardware-software installation and configuration.
- LAN-WAN Monitoring and Maintenance.
- Provide IT supports and troubleshooting to end users.
- Ability to provide accurate information on a prompt basis.
- Self- motivated individual, ability to work efficiently under pressure.

POS Support Manager of E-Services Department

-Point of Sale Technician in Oman Arab Bank

I am having experience and knowledge to integrated Point of Sale with PC System and stand alone system of POS. Else, the ability to troubleshoot PC & network equipment and strong communication & organization skills a must.

I am working Support and Maintained of POS for different government organizations and Private Companies in Oman Installing of POS Systems over Internet line with SSL protocol. Also, I have experience in Teller Workstation of SmartCard.

Key Strengths

- Ability to operate effectively as a member of a team in completing tasks, solving problem & working towards agreed goals.
- Good communicator with people from arang of backgrounds.

- High level of common sense and logical thought processes.
- Ability to learn new systems quickly with little instruction.
- Enjoy having responsibility.
- Ability to learn more of the computer industry and its applications.
- I am understanding of applications & database management as it relates specifically to TOS and Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) systems.
- Understanding of Terminal Operations, HR, financial and inventory control principles.
- I have Knowledge of Oracle and UNIX platforms, SQL, and Windows operating systems, with hands-on applications experience. Requires demonstrated proficiency with Oracle's internal mechanisms, SQL, and backup/recovery techniques.
- Knowledge of PC hardware and software systems and understanding of Oracle's database products. I know how to setup, maintain and troubleshoot Oracle databases.
- Ability and knowledge to troubleshoot a wide variety of applications and database management problems as they arise in the workplace.

Computer Skills

Specialized

Knowledge

- I have many courses and certifications from Oman Arab Bank in UNIX and ORACLE Certified Professional (OCPDBA).
- Ability to solve problems of high complexity.
- I have multi-task oriented with proven ability to manage several active projects simultaneously.
- I have detail oriented with a high degree of accuracy.
- Able to maintain confidentiality and act with discretion.
- Able to anticipate internal client needs and maintain good working relationships with users and management.
- I proficiency in various software applications and programs.
- Ability to communicate in English, both verbally and written.
 Arabic language skills helpful, especially in training others.
- I am excellent verbal and written communication skills.
- AS/400 Operator.
- Oracle Developer 2000.
- Database (Access, SQL express)

Soud Ali Habib AL-Jardani

- Designing: Photoshop and Paintshop.
- MS-Dos, MS Windows2000, Windows XP....
- Network Administration and configuration.
- Computer trouble shooting and maintenance.
- Visual Basic 6-0, Java, JavaScript, ASP, ASP.NET, Web Designing ...
- Microsoft Office Applications (MS Word, Excel, Access and Power Point)

Other Courses

Project Management Professional (PMP) Dec 2013

PMP Exam preparatory program

Microsoft Office 2013

Dec 2013

Microsoft Office 2013 Advanced

From Project Management Technology

Team Building

Dec 2013

From Index International Business Developing

Information Security Management System

Oct 2011

Information Security Consultancy Services and Compliance Consulting:

- Information Security Management System
- Internal Audits
- Security Policies & Procedure Formulation
- Risk Assessment
- Business Continuity Planning(BCP)
- Disaster Recovery Planning(DRP)

From **Infoline company**

CCNA Nov 2009

(Cisco Certified Network Associate)

from Polyglot Institute Oman I.I.c

Photoshop Jun 2009

from AL-Omani Institute

Languages Arabic (Speaking, Writing and Reading).

English (Speaking, Writing and Reading).

Course experience Training

AL-Royal Hospital

- Repairing and Maintenance center
- Experiences:
 - 1. Maintain and repair Hardware.
 - 2. Software Installation.
 - 3. Improve my communication skills with senior and other employees. Also, good analytical and problem solving skills.

Experience

I was work in khoula Hospital from 6/11/2001 until 8/7/2009.

I work in Oman Arab Bank from 2007 until now.

Additional activities

 Work as a team, in order to improve our knowledge and experience in modules, which I have learned.

Hobbies Football, Writing and Reading Poetry, Current Affairs, Using Internet,

Searching and watch TV.

References

Availability upon request.